# Peter Storli · pstorli@gmail.com · (971) 888-2534

20579 Noble Lane, West Linn, OR 97068

Resume: https://sites.google.com/site/pstorli/resume

Apps: https://sites.google.com/site/storlidesignsllc/apps

# **Android Software Engineer**

The **Smart Phone revolution** has arrived! Do you need a team player who has created quality software for fortune 500 companies for over 30 years?

Click **https://sites.google.com/site/storlidesignsllc** to see my design skills and steps for creating great software.

I am looking for positions in the Portland, OR area or remote/telecommuting.

#### TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- \* Android, Kotlin, Java, SQL, JQuery, JSON, Rest, Ajax, JavaScript, HTML, JSP, CSS, XML, UIX
- \* C, C++, Android Studio, Git, Gradle, JBoss, Ant, Junit, Spring, Bootstrap, Jira, Lucid Chart

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### PSS GIS App Developer · Elyon International · 2017-2018

Updated existing <u>S1 Mobile Mapper app</u> to allow the user to select desired theme. Also added new features and fixed bugs. App uses the <u>Environmental Systems</u> <u>Research Institute (ESRI)</u> suite and <u>ArcGIS Runtime SDK's</u> to display various maps. App can also collect map data even with no internet connection, which is useful when you are out in the forest mapping a trail.

Also created app to transfer files between devices using sockets and bluetooth. File transfer progress and file transfer can be cancelled at any time. Bluetooth can be enabled or disabled and nearby devices can be scanned for, selected, paired or unpaired.

# Android SW Engineer · ImageWare Systems · 2011-2017

Created GoVerifyID Android App that uses face, voice and fingerprint biometric modalities to verify your identity.

Frost & Sullivan Recognized GoVerifyID with its 2017 New Product Innovation Award.



Built several websites using java, spring, rest, jquery and bootstrap to manage and configure many of ImageWare's core products.

Developed new enterprise java bean enabled system which performs FBI criminal background checks and other tasks in the most flexible way by evaluating EBTS formatted files using a database driven state machine and xml configuration files.

Designed several GWT based tools to manage system, users and their credentials.

Also built graphical, Google Web Toolkit based EBTS file viewer and a configuration management program that uses java reflection, GWT and soap to dynamically mange all the company's products using xml based configuration files across multiple servers.

Visit: http://iwsinc.com

## Software Solutions Consultant · SingleMindConsulting · 2011-2011

Responsible for creating new John Deere portlet based web site using knowledge of Java Struts, Tiles, CSS and SQL. Liferay and Tomcat were used to house the portlet and a new GUI was built on top of Kona Kart to provide shopping cart functionality.

## Software Architect & Implementer · McAfee · Beaverton, OR · 2008-2010

Architected, Designed and Implemented several new McAfee products using mastery of front end, middle tier and backend components. Trained and experienced in developing software for a wide variety of McAfee customers. Designed and Implemented McAfee Operational Attributes EPO extension to keep track of a variety of attributes associated with EPO managed systems. Created java spring based software that imports LDAP directory from client system. Built C++ based program that stores a variety of client side data in the windows registry.

# Software Engineer · HP (PolyServe) · Beaverton, OR · 2004-2008

Designed and implemented user interface for Java Swing based clustered file system. Used by industries such as department of defense, internet, health care and banking to consolidate massive amounts of disk and CPU resources into a single cluster. Created new software wizard to install SQL on multiple servers in parallel. To learn more about my work on SQL Server Consolidation and Scalable File Serving

Visit: http://www.polyserve.com

## Programmer Analyst · Entertainment Partners · Burbank, CA · 2002-2004

Member of team that created new Java/XML/Swing based program used to schedule television and movie productions and create critical reports that coordinate activity on the set. This system is the replacement for the Movie Magic Scheduling system used on sets all over the world. Responsible for designing user interfaces for system, creating binary/xml file format used to save schedules and innovative event handling architecture. Used Rational Clear Case to build high level UML models for system and Rational Clear Quest for defect tracking. Learn about EP Scheduling.

Visit: http://webstore.entertainmentpartners.com

### Software Consultant · My Health Bank · Portland, OR · 2002-2002

Helped company meet critical deadline for finishing Java/JSP/SQL/XML based online insurance enrollment system.

### Software Consultant · Freightliner · Portland, OR · 2001-2002

Improved truck ordering system by building new Java Swing modules that allowed truck orders to be imported and exported in an xml based format. Also performed other user interface/system enhancements.

### Technical Lead · Unicru · Beaverton, OR · 1999-2001

Extended company's global reach by analyzing current phone based employment system, then designed and implemented Internet based system using Java, XML, HTML, JavaScript, and Transact SQL.

Created custom xml schema and trained others to create xml surveys customized to customer's look and feel without additional programming effort. A Java Servlet was used to generate dynamic html and JavaScript validation code from the survey xml. User data was stored from each page in the survey into a MS SQL database. The system has processed over 1 million applications for major fortune 500 companies such as Target, Blockbuster and Hollywood Video.

#### Visit: http://www.hirepro.com/blockbuster

## UI Project Lead · DRC · Beaverton, OR · 1998-1999

Consulted with resident fraud detection expert to design and implement user interface for telephone fraud detection system on Windows NT/95 platform. By using Microsoft Visual C++, MFC, Stingray's Objective Grid, SQL, ODBC and MDI (multiple document interface), users could view/manipulate multiple Oracle database tables containing suspected fraud cases. To help the marketing and sales teams, the system could also be seamlessly used with a small demo Access database on a laptop.

Designed an administration tool that let non- technical users customize program logic and data. Because of the object-orientated nature of the programs, a large amount of the code was shared between the two applications. This product detected fraud by processing over 55 million phone calls per day at Southern Bell California.

### Software Engineer · Digitech Solutions · Beaverton, OR · 1996-1998

Designed and built user interface for internet based utility billing system utilizing Microsoft Visual C++, MFC and Paint Shop Pro. System consolidated utility bills for all stores of major retailers. Added detailed custom bitmap images, animated movie sequences and sound effects to make superior product.

### Software Engineer · Rapidfire Software · Hillsboro, OR · 1996-1996

Developed point of sale application for the restaurant business with MS Visual C++ using many of the new GUI objects available in Windows95.

## Software Engineer · Performance computing · Beaverton, OR · 1995-1995

Developed the user interface for real time PC based audio/video phone system using C and MS Windows SDK. Designed GUI for system administration portion of XTerminal based teleconferencing system using C and MS Windows NT.

## Software Consultant · Princeton Info · Colorado Springs, CO · 1995-1995

Ported IBM PC 3270 server emulator to new GUI platform, created toolbar buttons with floating text, and other reusable C++/GUI objects for a common class library using Borland C++ 4.5, MS Windows 3.1 and Zapp 2.2.

## Software Engineer · Telos Consulting · Colorado Springs, CO · 1994-1995

Created satellite monitoring system to control local and remote sites. Programmed the user interface of the system in record time using Microsoft Visual C++ with Foundation Classes (MFC) and MS Windows NT. Created displays that allowed users to scroll an unlimited number of icon images of satellites in various states, as well as other color-coded status information.

Developed the user interface for a 3D missile tracking simulation on Silicon Graphics workstations using UNIX, X-Designer, and C++. Eliminated tedious hand calculations by allowing users to switch between various coordinate systems and units of measurement using C and OSF/Motif. Made system more realistic by porting maps from the CIA World Database.

## Software Engineer · DRC · Colorado Springs, CO · 1994-1994

Used Oracle Forms, 4GL (PL/SQL), and other MS Windows programs to analyze, design and code a multi-platform (HP and MS Windows) configuration management system that consolidated a variety of different user databases.

Developed a chart that tracked the lifecycle of document changes using the CAD package Microstation.

# Software Engineer · USAF · Colorado Springs, CO · 1989-1994

Designed graphical user interfaces for real time message processing system using Ada, XWindows, DECWindows and Framemaker on VAX/VMS, Rational and Sun Sparcstation. Created reusable graphic utilities to quickly build forms and tables cutting development time by 40%. Reduced

programming effort by allowing users to create their own displays.

### Software Configuration Manager · USAF · Colorado Springs, CO · 1988-1989

Installed software and tracked software change requests. Saved 50% of distribution time by developing DBASEIII application under MS DOS to automate manual system.

### Computer Repair Technician · USAF · Misawa, Japan · 1984-1988

Granted TOP SECRET clearance to maintain and repair a wide variety of computers. As a highly qualified technician, often worked overtime to train others and minimize downtime.

#### Vice President · Robotix Inc. · Abilene, TX · 1983-1984

Designed and implemented software for the company's first mobile talking robot using BASIC, Assembly language and a Commodore 64 computer.

### **EDUCATION**

BS, Computer Science (3.93 GPA) Colorado Technical College 1992
A.A.S., Computer Maintenance (3.94) Air Force Community College 1992
OO Analysis & Design Using UML Sun Microsystems 2003
Developing XML Solutions Oregon Graduate Institute 2001
Oracle Reports Course Oracle Corporation 1994
Ada Certificate Colorado Technical College 1992
DECWindows Programming Course Digital Equipment Corporation 1989
Programming Specialist Training (3.97) Keesler Air Force Base 1988
Computer Repair Training (3.91) Keesler Air Force Base 1984
HOBBIES

- \* Hot Springs, Skiing, Hiking, Gardening and running hobby farm.
- \* Building Google Android smart phone strategy/action games.

President & CTO · Storli Designs L.L.C. · 2013-Present

- \* Created Tiger2D, an Android OpenGLES Game Engine that makes it simple to create blazingly fast 2D games quickly!
- \* Created DreamWeaver Android smart phone application for Deepak Chopra that uses images, strobing lights, music and narration to put you in a relaxed state of mind. DreamWeaver Screen Shots
- \* Click PlayPokerDice to play GWT game. PlayPokerDice Screen Shots
- \* Created Bitcoin Wallet Android App for StashCrypto and Monetas that lets perform bitcoin transactions just like you can do with a checking account.

Have a look at my resume:

# https://sites.google.com/site/pstorli/resume

as well as apps that have been published in the Google Play Store

https://sites.google.com/site/storlidesignsllc/apps